Guide to the Robert Earl Cushman Papers, 1915; 1941-1988 UA.29.02.0159
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Duke University Administrative Materials, 1944-1986; 1
  - Student Dissent, 1953-1983; 4
    Files include materials and clippings about students and faculty—at Duke and nationwide—involved in civil disobedience and activism; and material on the internal Divinity School self-studies. There is also a file on the prayer service in the aftermath of the MLK assassination, and some redacted files on minority students at the Divinity School and on the Divinity School’s use of the Minnesota Multiphasic Personality Inventory to provide psychological profiles. Some materials relate to James Cannon’s time as dean of the Divinity School in the 1950s. Material about the Divinity School self-study and curriculum review is also included in the Committees and Operations subseries. The subseries is arranged chronologically.
    - Student Problems (Personal), 1953 (Box 7)
    - Student Problems (Personal), 1953-1959 (Box 7)
    - Student Problems (Academic), 1958-1962 (Box 7)
    - Ingram Memoranda, 1959-1969 (Box 7)
    - Students - Arrest and Trial, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Vanderbilt Affair, 1960 May 31 (Box 7)
    - Student Testing Scores - MMPI, 1960-1962 (Box 7)
    - Mississippi Crisis (Chicago Daily News), 1962 October 1 (Box 7)
    - Hillsboro Cases: Professors - Civil Disobedience, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Civil Rights, 1964-1965 (Box 7)
    - University and Student Unrest, 1965-1971; 2 Files (Box 7)
    - Welch, Donald J., 1965-1969 (Box 7)
    - Duke Board of Trustees, 1966 (Box 7)
    - Vietnam, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Pastors' School Instructors, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Perkins School of Theology: Governance Procedures, 1967-1970 (Box 7)
    - Hornets: Faculty Remonstrance, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Civil Disobedience, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Martin Luther King Event, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Special Faculty Meeting - Divinity School, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Student Vigil - Tisdale Statement, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Vigil for Non-Academic Employee, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Student Trial, 1969 (Box 7)
    - Concerned Students, 1969 February (Box 7)
    - Divinity School Government Structure Documents, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
    - Policy Statements of Dean, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
    - Committee of Seven for Structural Study, 1968-1969 (Box 8)
    - Student Participation Standing Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
    - Financial Aid: Admissions, Student Dissent, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
    - State of Divinity School, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
    - School Issues: Board of Visitors Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
    - Crisis Year Documents, 1969-1970 (Box 8)
    - Student Dissent, 1969 (Box 8)
    - Student Dissent: Subversion, 1969-1971; 2 Files (Box 8)
    - Faculty Executive Council, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Statements of Student Assembly, Financial Aid, AATS Self-Study, etc., 1970 (Box 8)
    - Student Crisis: Week of April 21-29, 1970, 1970 April 21-29 (Box 8)
    - Robinson Affair, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Student-FEC Conferences, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Divinity School Self-Study Commission, 1970-1971; 2 Files (Box 8)
    - OT 11 (Efird) Case, 1970, 1978 (Box 8)
      Restricted until 2048
    - Student Publication Dissent, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
    - Report of Self-Study, 1983 (Box 8)
- Professional Activities, 1947-1984; 2
  Includes correspondence with colleagues; clippings; photographs; and files on Cushman’s involvement with Methodist Church committees, especially in regard to Methodist participation in ecumenism and Methodist theological education. Also includes files about Cushman’s involvement in worldwide and nationwide Christian ecumenism and theological schools of various Christian denominations; and materials relating to his participation as a Protestant observer at the Second Vatican Council of the Roman Catholic Church. Arranged into four subseries: Professional Correspondence; Methodist Church Activities; Theological Schools and Ecumenical Files; and Second Vatican Council.
  - Professional Correspondence, 1959-1979; 5
    Contains correspondence with colleagues primarily outside of Duke University, such as heads of other theological schools, associates from the Second Vatican Council, Methodist bishop William Cannon, and others. This subseries is filed alphabetically by correspondent last name or subject of the correspondence.
    - Altizer, Thomas J. J., 1965-1966 (Box 8)
    - Anderson, Bernhard, 1963-1970 (Box 8)
    - Father Anthony, 1968-1971 (Box 8)
    - Belmont Abbey College, 1970 (Box 8)
    - Belmont Abbey College, 1966 May 24 (Box 8)
    - Bennett, John Coleman, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Blackburn, Bishop Robert M., 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - Binkley, Dean Olin: Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary, 1961-1971 (Box 8)
    - Bowles, Dr. Charles P., 1963-1966 (Box 8)
    - Brauer, Dean Jerald C., 1962-1969 (Box 9)
    - Cannon, Bishop William R., 1968-1980 (Box 9)
    - Cannon, Bishop William R., 1967-1977 (Box 9)
    - Cavert, Samuel McCrea: Union Seminary, 1963 (Box 9)
    - Centenary College, Lousiana Conference, North Mississippi Conference, 1965-1966 (Box 9)
    - "Church and Renewal in the World" Columbia, SC, 1966 (Box 9)
    - Colwell, Ernest C., 1966-1968 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence in Connection with the Vatican Council, 1963-1966 (Box 9)
    - Crum, Jack, 1968-1971 (Box 9)
    - Day, Peter, 1974-1975 (Box 9)
    - Dickhaut, John W., 1959-1965 (Box 9)
    - Dickson, Fagan, 1974-1976 (Box 9)
    - Drew University - Madison, NJ, 1970 (Box 9)
    - Dunn, Dr. Van Bogard, 1959-1969 (Box 9)
    - Dunn, Dr. Van Bogard, 1979 (Box 9)
    - Engagements (Past), 1959, 1963-1964 (Box 9)
    - Engagements (Past), 1964-1965; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Engagements (Past), 1965-1966 (Box 9)
    - European Travel Plans, 1963 (Box 9)
    - Gamboa, Chaplain Jose C., Jr. - Philippine Wesleyan College, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
    - Gettemy, James N.: Hartford Seminary Foundation, 1965 (Box 9)
    - Griswold, Dr. Whitney A., President of Yale University, 1962 (Box 9)
    - Gross, Dr. John O., 1960-1971 (Box 9)
    - Hamilton, Harold P., 1959-1971 (Box 9)
    - Harmon, Bishop Nolan B., 1974-1976 (Box 9)
    - Holt, D. D., President of Scarlet College Nashville, TN - Pfeiffer College Misenheimer, NC, 1964-1976 (Box 9)
    - Houston, Dr. Robert W., 1973-1974 (Box 9)
    - Huston, Hollis W., 1967-1969 (Box 9)
    - Kirkpatrick, Dow, 1968 (Box 9)
    - McCulloh, Gerald O.: Board of Education, 1968-1977 (Box 9)
    - McCulloh, Gerald O.: Current, 1968-1971 (Box 9)
    - McCulloh, Gerald O.: Methodist Board of Education, 1958-1967; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - McKay, Orville H., 1965-1970 (Box 9)
    - Miller, Dean Samuel H., 1962 (Box 9)
    - Muelder, Dean Walter G., 1962-1970 (Box 9)
    - Nelson, Fletcher, 1961-1979 (Box 9)
    - Nelson, Fletcher, 1965-1970 (Box 9)
    - Nelson, Fletcher, 1965-1976 (Box 9)
    - Nestbit, Wilson, 1963-1976 (Box 10)
    - Niebuhr, H. Richard, 1962 (Box 10)
    - Outler, A. C., 1966-1980 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973-1977 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974-1978 (Box 10)
    - Quillian, Joseph D., Jr. (Dean), 1959-1971; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Ramsey, Paul, 1958-1971 (Box 10)
    - Ranson, Charles (Dean), 1966 (Box 10)
    - Rurak, Reverend Henry, 1968-1970 (Box 10)
    - Schafer, Tom A., 1961-1967 (Box 10)
    - Sewall, John Ives, 1969-1973 (Box 10)
    - Shipley, David, 1971 (Box 10)
    - Sittler, Joseph, 1961-1966 (Box 10)
    - Stokes, Mack B. (Candler), 1959-1968 (Box 10)
    - Taylor, Eben: Visiting Alumnus Lecturer, 1965-1971 (Box 10)
    - Taylor, Kenneth, 1968-1972 (Box 10)
    - Thigpen, Richard E., 1960-1961 (Box 10)
    - Trott, Norman L., 1959-1973 (Box 10)
    - Watts, Ewart G., 1973 (Box 10)
    - Weldon, Dr. Wilson O., 1968-1971 (Box 10)
    - Wesley Theology Seminary, 1962-1969 (Box 10)
    - Yzermans, Monsignor Vincet A., 1968-1978 (Box 10)
  - Methodist Church Files, 1947-1984; 6
    Focuses on the conferences and committees Cushman served on within the wider Methodist Church. Includes files on The Association of Methodist Theological Schools (AMTS, later AUMTS), Methodist ecumenical commissions, and the Methodist General Conference. Some of the AMTS files may overlap particularly with the Divinity School self-study and curriculum review files contained in Series 1: Duke University Administrative Materials. Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - AMTS Minutes, 1958-1965; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - AMTS Minutes, 1965-1970; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - AMTS Church Support for the Theological Schools, 1964-1965 (Box 10)
    - AMTS Executive Council Business, 1964-1969 (Box 10)
    - AMTS 1965 Meetings Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 10)
    - AMTS Study of Financial Needs and Resources for Theological Education, 1965-1967 (Box 10)
    - AMTS 1967 Faculty Convocation, 1965, 1969 (Box 10)
    - AMTS 1966 Meetings Correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 10)
    - AMTS Correspondence re. past meetings, 1966-1967 (Box 10)
    - AMTS Manifesto, 1966-1967; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - AMTS Miscellaneous Documents, 1967 (Box 10)
    - AMTS Meeting January 27-28 1968, 1967-1968 (Box 10)
    - AMTS Annual Meeting: Sheraton Jefferson Hotel, Dayton, OH, 1968 (Box 10)
    - AUMTS Student Enlistments (Likins), 1969 (Box 11)
    - AUMTS Meetings and Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 11)
    - AUMTS: Nashville, Tennessee, 1970-1971 (Box 11)
    - Association of the United Methodist Seminars, 1969? (Box 11)
    - Black Power - Civil Rights, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Board of Education, The United Methodist Church - Nashville, TN, 1959-1971; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - COCU: Consultations on Church Union, 1965-1968 (Box 11)
    - COCU: Methodism, 1967 (Box 11)
    - COCU: Consultation on Church Union, 1969 (Box 11)
    - COCU: Plan of Union, 1970 (Box 11)
    - Committee on Alternative Rituals, Commission on Worship - Chicago, 1971 (Box 11)
    - Drew University Crisis, 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: Commission on Ecumenical Consultation, 1957-1964 (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: Commission on Ecumenical Consultation, 1959-1966; 3 folders (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: Commission on Ecumenical Consultation, 1964-1966 (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: Huston, Robert W. - General Secretary, Commission on Ecumenical Affairs, 1965-1970 (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: Commission on Ecumenical Affairs - Sunday Papers, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: Commission on Ecumenical Affairs, 1966-1968; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: Commission on Ecumenical Affairs, 1967-1968 (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: United Methodist Guide to Ecumenical Commitment, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: General Commission on Ecumenical Affairs, 1969 (Box 11)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: General Commission on Ecumenical Affairs, 1969-1971 (Box 12)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: Paper 1969 "Some Ecumenical Dimension in Theological Education" Commission on Ecumenical Affairs (Box 12)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: Dr. Robert E. Cushman Executive Committee CEA, 1970 (Box 12)
    - Ecumenical Affairs, 1971-1972 (Box 12)
    - Ecumenical Affairs: General Commission on Ecumenical Affairs, Executive Committee Meeting St. Louis, 1971 (Box 12)
    - Financial Needs of Theological Education - Report, 1967 (Box 12)
    - General Conference of the Methodist Church, 1960 (Box 12)
    - General Conference of the Methodist Church Memorials, 1964 (Box 12)
    - General Conference, 1964 (Box 12)
    - General Conference: Evangelical United Brethren Merger Plan, 1964 (Box 12)
    - General Conference: Methodist General Conference Committee, Chicago, 1966 (Box 12)
    - General Conference Documents, 1968 (Box 12)
    - General Conference, 1968 (Box 12)
    - General Conference 1968 Legislative Materials, 1966-1968 (Box 12)
    - General Conference, 1970 (Box 12)
    - General Conference: Correspondence concerning Generael Conference Memorials, 1963-1964 (Box 12)
    - Louisiana Methodist Conference: Gov. McKeithen's Address, 1966 (Box 12)
    - General Conference: Denominational Decision Making Case Study - J. M. Ormond Center, 1979 (Box 12)
    - Interpreter's House - Lake Junaluska, 1967-1969; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Methodist Bishops' Addresses, 1984 (Box 12)
    - Department of Ministerial Education: Special Study of the Methodist Theological Studies, 1962-1963 (Box 12)
    - United Methodist Church Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 12)
    - Methodism Clippings, 1947-1951 (Box 12)
    - German Methodism, 1957 (Box 12)
    - North Carolina Conference: Commission on Ecumenical Affairs, 1967-1971 (Box 12)
    - North Carolina Conference, 1973-1980 (Box 12)
    - North Carolina Conference Business, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
    - On the Ministry, 1955-1956, 1959 (Box 12)
    - One Percent Plan, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
    - Re-Write of Desciplines - Ministry, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
    - Southeastern Jurisdiction Conference - Lake Junaluska, NC, 1968 (Box 12)
    - University Senate of the Meathodist Church Documents, 1965-1967; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - University Senate of the Meathodist Church Documents, 1965-1971 (Box 13)
    - Wesley Society, 1957-1963 (Box 13)
    - World Methodist Conference, OSLO, 1960 (Box 13)
    - World Methodist Council Conference, England, 1966 (Box 13)
    - World Methodist Council: Oxford Institute, 1981-1982 (Box 13)
  - Theological Schools and Ecumenism Files, 1948-1984; 7
    This subseries contains files about ecumenical initiatives and theological education in which Cushman participated that are not centered on the Methodist churches and schools but that are made up of various Christian denominations. Includes files on the Ecumenical Institute for Advanced Theological Studies in Jerusalem, including clippings on the Middle East in general and a recording by King Hussein of Jordan on the subject of Jerusalem; files on the World Council of Churches; and general files on ecumenical and educational issues, including ATS (American Association of Theological Schools). Files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - General Files: National Council of Chruches, 1963-1970; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - General Files: Ecumenical and Unity Services, 1965-1966 (Box 13)
    - General Files: Roman Catholic Leadership Personnel, 1966-1967 (Box 13)
    - General Files: North Carolina Council of Churches, 1968-1973 (Box 13)
    - General Files: Latin American Catholicism after 2nd Vatican Council, 1968 (Box 13)
    - General Files: Canon Law School Symposium Dayton, OH, 1969 (Box 13)
    - General Files: Theological Education and Clergy, 1971 (Box 13)
    - General Files: American Theological Society (ATS), 1972-1984 (Box 13)
    - General Files: American Theological Society (ATS), 1972 (Box 13)
    - General Files: American Theological Society (ATS) - Avery Dulles, S. J. 1979 Address (Box 13)
    - General Files: Theological Education Developments and Centers, 1967 (Box 13)
    - AATS Catholic Membership, Maryknoll Meeting, 1966 (Box 13)
    - AATS Bulletin, 1970 (Box 13)
    - AATS: Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1960-1970 (Box 13)
    - AATS: Jesse H. Ziegler Correspondence, 1961-1970 (Box 13)
    - AATS: Staff Reports, 1962-1967; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - AATS: Executive Committee, 1962-1968; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - AATS Biennial Meeting - St. Louis, 1968 (Box 13)
    - AATS: Report of the Committee on the Professional Doctorate as a First Degree, 1969-1971 (Box 13)
    - AATS: Harvard Divinity School Visitation, 1970 (Box 13)
    - AATS: Evaluation at Duke Divinity School, 1970 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Institution of Advanced Ecumenical Studies - Jerusalem (creation of), 1965 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Ecumenical Institute for Advanced Theological Studies - Jerusalem, 1970-1978 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Jerusalem and Institute, 1971-1978; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Palestine - Christmas and Festivals, Jerusalem, 1971-1973 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Jerusalem Ecumenical Institute - Colleagues Correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Interfaith Conference in Palestine - Ingram Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: St. Georges College - Jerusalem, 1973 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Tantur Institute Newsletter, 1982 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Israel Clippings, 1969-1976 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Israel Clippings, 1971-1973 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: "Jerusalem in Captivity" - A Personal Message from H.M. King Hussein of Jordan, 1972 (Audio-phonodisc UA29020159-PD-0001)
      Arrangement
      This item has been separated from the "Middle East: Israel Clippings, 1971-1973" file, which contains a 1972 letter that accompanied the audio recording.
    - Middle East: Judaism Clippings, 1973-1974 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Palestine and Middle East Clippings, 1972-1974 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Palestine: Israel - Internal Affairs Clippings, 1972-1974 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Palestine Mixed Clippings, 1973-1978 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Arab Nations Clippings, 1973-1976 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: Israeli State Clippings, 1973-1976 (Box 14)
    - Middle East: World Reaction, 1973-1976 (Box 14)
    - Middle East-Russia-USA, 1973-1974 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Church Unity - Ecumenism, 1948-1954 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Third World Conference on Faith and Order - Lund, Sweden, 1952 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Addresses - Lund, Hug. (Brilioth et al.), 1952 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Successive Drafts of Lund Report, 1952 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Lund Report and Constitution (Official Final Version), 1952 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Photograph - Lund Conference, 1952 (Oversize-folder 2)
    - World Council of Churches: Lund (Hungarian Commentary), 1952 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Commission on Worship, 1954-1959; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Commission on Worship, 1960-1962 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Oberlin Conference, 1957 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Oberlin Conference, 1957 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Correspondence (Ecumenism), 1959-1965 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Confidential Communications, 1960-1962 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Faith and Order - Montreal, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Montreal Conference Report, 1963 (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Conference on Faith and Order, 1963; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - World Council of Churches: Montreal Conference written Critiques for Section IV, 1963 (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches: Montreal Conference - Papers and Agenda, 1963; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches: Montreal Conference, 1963 (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches: Montreal - Notes, 1963 (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches: Secretariat on Religious Liberty, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches: Uppsala Communication, 1968 (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches: United States Conference, 1968-1969 (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches, 1972-1975 (Box 15)
  - Second Vatican Council, 1963-1971; 8
    Focuses on Cushman’s role as a Protestant observer at Sessions 2, 3, and 4 of the Second Vatican Council of the Roman Catholic Church. It includes his notes on some of the sessions; drafts of the major documents produced by the council, with his comments and notes; some correspondence about the trip; official bulletins about the proceedings of three sessions; official photographs of the council participants; and some written reflections Cushman gave or published regarding his views as a Methodist observer. Additional materials about the Second Vatican Council can be found in the Professional Correspondence subseries of Series 2: Professional Activities, and in Series 3: Writings; and may also be present in Series 4: Personal Files. Oversize magazines include Cushman’s notes on articles about the Council. This subseries is arranged into general files (largely by session); documents produced at the Council; and news bulletins.
    - Photos (Box 15)
    - Photos (Box 15)
    - Clippings, Memorabilia, and Miscellaneous Documents, 1963 (Box 15)
    - Clippings, Memorabilia, and Miscellaneous Documents, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - Clippings, Memorabilia, and Miscellaneous Documents, 1964 (Box 15)
    - Clippings, Memorabilia, and Miscellaneous Documents, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - Clippings, Memorabilia, and Miscellaneous Documents, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
    - Clippings, Memorabilia, and Miscellaneous Documents, 1971 (Box 15)
    - Magazines (Oversize-folder 3)
    - First Session, 1962 (Box 15)
    - Second Session: Notes, 1963 (Box 15)
    - Special Masses, 1963 (Box 15)
    - Second Session: Vatican Council Clippings, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - Second Session: Commendations of Vatican II Report, 1964 (Box 15)
    - Observers, 1963-1965 (Box 15)
    - Papal Discourses, 1963 (Box 15)
    - Rome Trip Fall 1963, 1962-1963 (Box 15)
    - Cushman Commentary, 1963 (Box 15)
    - Ecumenical Challenge to Methodism (Junaluska), 1963 (Box 15)
    - Third Session: A Protestant Report on Vatican Council II, circa 1964 (Box 15)
    - Third Session Clippings, 1964 (Box 15)
    - Third Session: Federal Council of Protestant Churches in Italy, 1964 (Box 15)
    - Papal Discourse: Paul VI, 1964 (Box 15)
    - Rome Trip Fall 1964 (Box 15)
    - Audience Observers with Paul VI, 1964 (Box 15)
    - Clippings - Barbara Cushman Article, 1964-1967 (Box 15)
    - Articles by Dean Cushman on the Second Vatican Council, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
    - Fourth Session, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Fourth Session: Remarks, R.E.C., [1965?] (Box 15)
    - Fourth Session: Clippings, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Fourth Session, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Fourth Session, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Fourth Session: Final Report, 1966 (Box 15)
    - Final Ceremonies with Observers, 1965 (Box 15)
    - Rome Trip Fall 1965 (Box 15)
    - "Informal" Lecture, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
    - Methodist Church in Rome: Keighley, Rev. D. Alan, 1965 (Box 15)
    - "Ecumenism and Renewal", 1966 (Box 15)
    - Roman Catholic Church: Birth Control - Pastoral Statements, 1966 (Box 15)
    - Council Documents: De Sacra Liturgia, 1963 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: De Ecclesia - Strugnell's Translation, 1963 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: De Ecclesia - Strugnell's Translation, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Divine Revelation, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: De Divinia Revelatione, 1964-1965 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: The Church in the Modern World, undated (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: On Catholic Schools, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: On Jews and Religious Liberty - De Oecumenismo, 1963-1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Declaration on Religious Freedom, 1965-1966 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Declaration on Religious Liberty, 1965 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Catholic-Jewish Relations, undated (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Non-Christian Religions, 1965 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Instrumentis Communicationis, 1963 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Oriental Churches, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: On Bishops and the Government of Dioceses, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: On Liturgy, 1965 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Ecumenism, 1963-1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: On Religion, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Of Missions, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: On the Lay Apostolate, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: On Priesthood VII, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Sacrament and Matrimony, 1964 (Box 16)
    - Council Documents: Miscellaneous Copies, 1965, undated (Box 16)
    - News Bulletins: Second Session, 1963; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - News Bulletins: Third Session, 1964 (Box 16)
    - News Bulletins: Third Session, 1964 (Box 16)
    - News Bulletins: Third Session, 1964 (Box 16)
    - News Bulletins: Fourth Session, 1965 (Box 16)